Cruiser Houston Collection, 1917-2003
University of Houston Libraries
- ARTICLES, 1941-2000
  - What’s in a Name? Our Navy, July 1944 (photocopy). (Box 22, Folder 26)
- CLIPPINGS, 1929-2002
  The clippings were organized during two different periods using two different methods. The first batch was arranged by topic, while the second batch was sorted only by date. The researcher looking for information on a particular topic should check not only the topical folders but also the date-only folders to make sure he has found all related clippings.
  Due to the fragility of newsprint, all of the newspaper clippings have been photocopied onto less acidic paper.
  - Australian POWs/HMAS Perth, 1976-1988. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Australian POWs/HMAS Perth, 1982-1994 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Battle of the Java Sea, 1942-1945 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Battle of the Java Sea, 1942-1945 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Battle of the Java Sea, 1942-1946 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Boxing; Frank Pistole, [ca. 1942] and undated. (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Boxing, John Wisecup [ca. 1938-39]. (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Burma-Thai railway, 1958-1994 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Burma-Thai railway, 1959-1982 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Burma-Thai railway, 1992 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Crew members MIA/KIA, 1942-1944, undated (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Cruiser Houston…Sunk at Java, Cleveland Press, 1942 (original and copy). (Ovs OVS)
  - 50th Anniversary, Sinking of the USS Houston (CA-30), 1992. (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - 50th Anniversary, Sinking of the USS Houston (CA-30), 1992 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Houston Volunteers, 1942-1974 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - The Katy Times, 1999, 2002. (Box 23, Folder 15)
    Donor: Jerry Waxman
  - Dr. Farrel W. Keith, undated. (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Guthrie F. Layne, Jr., [1942]. (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Lost Battalion Association, 1976-1988. (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Samuel McMaster, Pittsburgh, [ca. 1942]. (Box 23, Folder 19)
    Donor: Bridget McMaster
  - Other Allied ships, 1997 and undated (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - POW Camp Experiences, [ca. 1994]. (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - POWs flag, 1955. (Box 23, Folder 22)
    Donor: Dean Wood
  - POWs, [1942-1945]. (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - Punchbowl Cemetery plaque, 1994. (Box 23, Folder 24)
  - River Kwai, 1982. (Box 23, Folder 25)
    Donor: Leonard "Dutch" Kooper
  - Saga of a Stout Ship, New York Times Magazine, 1946. (Box 23, Folder 26)
  - Silver Service, 1930. (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Silver Service, 1929-1943 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Survivors reunions, 1956-1985 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - USS Houston (CA-30), 1942 (Box 55, Folder 7)
  - USS Houston (CA-30), 1942. (Box 24, Folder 4)
    Donor: Louis Garbs
  - USS Houston (CA-30), 1943-1993 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - USS Houston (CA 30), 1942 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - USS Houston (CA-30) memorials, [ca. 1945]-1995 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - USS Houston (CA-30) Monument, [ca. 1990s]. (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - USS Houston (CA-30) pilots, [ca. 1940s] (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - USS Houston (CA-30) Survivors, 1942-1956 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - USS Houston (CA-30) Survivors, 1971 -1994 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - USS Houston (CL 81), 1942-1995 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - USS Houston (SSN 713) launch, 1981. (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - USS Houston (SSN 713) launch, 1981 (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - USS Houston Survivors Association Reunion, 1997. (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - War bond drive, 1942 (Box 55, Folder 8)
  - War bond drive, 1942 (Box 55, Folder 9)
  - William J. Weissinger, undated (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Clippings, [1930]. (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Clippings, ca. 1935. (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Clippings, 1936 (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - Clippings, 1942-1945. (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - Clippings, 1943-1994. (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - Clippings, 1944. (Box 24, Folder 22)
  - Clippings, 1945, 1995. (Box 24, Folder 23)
  - Clippings, 1945 and undated (Box 24, Folder 24)
  - Clippings, 1945, 1997. (Box 24, Folder 25)
  - Clippings, 1963-1983. (Box 24, Folder 26)
  - Clippings, 1967 (Box 24, Folder 27)
  - Clippings, 1979 (Box 24, Folder 28)
  - Clippings, 1982. with letter from Leonard “Dutch” Kooper, August 31, 1982. (Box 24, Folder 29)
  - Clippings, 1982. (Box 24, Folder 30)
  - Clippings, 1982-1985. (Box 24, Folder 31)
  - Clippings, 1982-1984 (Box 24, Folder 32)
  - Clippings, 1985. (Box 24, Folder 33)
  - Clippings, 1985-1986 (Box 24, Folder 34)
  - Clippings, 1994 (Box 24, Folder 35)
  - Clipping, 1997. (Ovs OVS)
    Donor: Jack Feliz
  - Clippings, 2000 and undated. (Box 24, Folder 36)
  - Clippings, undated. (Box 24, Folder 37)
  - Clippings, undated. (Box 24, Folder 38)
- PERSONAL ACCOUNTS
  This series contains accounts of events related to the USS Houston (CA030) and the POW experience, as recollected by individuals who directly experienced them. Most of these personal accounts were given many decades after the original events.
  - And God Was There, undated (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Charles Atterberry, letter from Mattie Atterberry to Otto Schwarz, December 18, 1990. (Box 25, Folder 2)
    Donor: Mattie Atterberry
  - Raymond Day, Saga of the Houston, undated, with Inventory of Clinical Records. (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - M.V. Eddy, letter from Eddy to Otto Schwarz, El Cajon, CA, June 20, 1980. (Box 25, Folder 4)
    Donor: Merritt V. Eddy
  - Tom Falloon, My Brush with History. Donor: USS San Juan Shipmates (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Robert B. Fulton, account of Paul Gyugo, September 16, 1989. (Box 25, Folder 6)
    Donor: Robert B. Fulton
  - Robert B. Fulton, account of Caswell Mayo, October 4, 1983 (photocopy). (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Presidential Cruise 1938, [ca. 1988]. (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Otto Schwarz. American POWs in Saigon (1944-1945), 2002. (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Otto Schwarz, Wreath laying ceremony in Sunda Strait, 1981. (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Jack Smith, personal accounts. (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - T.H. Moorer, Recollections on USS Houston, February 28, 1972 (photocopy). (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - The Story of Lieutenant (jg) Francis Weiler's U.S. Naval Academy Class Ring. (Box 25, Folder 13)
    Donor: Jack and Pat Mintzer
  - William J. Weissinger Jr., interviewed by Samuel Milner, August 12 and August 19, 1959. (Box 25, Folder 14)
- TYPESCRIPTS/HISTORICAL ACCOUNTS
  This series contains both typescripts prepared for potential publication, and fact-based accounts of various aspects of the USS Houston (CA-30) story. Materials are arranged alphabetically by author.
  - T.R. Beaton, A Traveller’s Guide to the Burma Railway, 2003. (Box 25, Folder 15)
    Donor: Terry Beaton
  - Carter B. Conlin, Ship's Bell of USS Houston (CA-30), 1991 (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Lost Battalion Association, undated (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Samuel Milner, Introduction and Chapter 3, The Undefeated: An Epic For Our Time; 1987(photocopies). (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Samuel Milner, [Introduction], The Undefeated. (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - Samuel Milner, Java and After: The Project in Outline. (Box 25, Folder 20)
  - Samuel Milner, Statement of Plans For Research, undated (Box 25, Folder 21)
  - Samuel Milner, The Undefeated: The Project in Outline, undated (photocopy). (Box 25, Folder 22)
  - Office of Naval Records and History, History of USS Houston (CA-30), 1949. (Box 25, Folder 23)
  - Office of Naval Records and History, History of USS Houston (CA-30), revised by USS Houston Survivors Association/Next Generation, 1995 (Box 25, Folder 24)
  - David P. Robrock, Dedication of the Cruiser Houston Memorial Exhibit and the George R. Brown Room, 1981 (Box 25, Folder 25)
  - The Scouting Cruiser Houston, ca. 1994. (Box 25, Folder 26)
  - USS Houston (CA-30), background for USS Houston (SSN-713) memorial service, April 1993. (Box 25, Folder 27)
    Donor: Otto Schwarz.
- ORAL HISTORIES
  This series contains two bound transcripts of oral history interviews done with Houston survivors by the University of North Texas Oral History Program. Patrons are welcome to read the oral histories in the Special Collections reading room, but anyone wishing photocopies of the transcripts must contact the University of North Texas Oral History Program directly.
  - Melford L. Forsman, University of North Texas Oral History Collection. (Box 25, Folder 28)
    Donor: Melford E. "Gus" Forsman
  - Otto Schwarz, University of North Texas Oral History Collection. (Box 25, Folder 29)
- COMMEMORATIVE BOOKLETS
  Most of the booklets in this series are bound, photocopied collections of articles, photographs, poems, etc. that were created by Houston survivors to commemorate their experiences. They are arranged alphabetically by creator.
  - The Cruiser Houston Story - Circa 1924-1983 - How Did It Happen-When and Where, [ca. 1983]. (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Carl H. Fritsche, USS Houston, 131st Field Artillery, 7th Bomb Group and the River Kwai Data Collection. (Box 26, Folder 2)
    Donor: Carl H. Fritsche
  - John C. Reas, The Real Story of the Bridge on the River Kwai, 2001. (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - John C. Reas, Story of the Survivor/Death Lists: Men of the USS Houston Showing Who Died Constructing the Burma-Siam Railway, 1998. (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - John C. Reas, USS Houston CA-30 Survivors Reunion and Memorial Service, 1998. (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - John C. Reas, USS Houston CA-30 Survivors and The Next Generation Reunion and Memorial Service, 1999. (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - John C. Reas, USS Houston CA-30 Survivors and The Next Generation Reunion and Memorial Service, 2000. (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - John C. Reas, USS Houston CA-30 Survivors and The Next Generation Reunion and Memorial Service, 2001. (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - The Saga of the USS Houston: Harold M. Johnson. (Box 28, Folder 3)
    Donor: Family of Harold M. Johnson
  - George D. Stoddard, The Sinking of the USS Houston and Life In Japanese Prison Camps, March 3, 2001. (Box 26, Folder 3)
    Donor: Marilyn Messier
  - USS Houston and POW Camps booklet (Ghost of the Java Coast cover). (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - USS Houston and POW Camps booklet (Navy Combat cover). (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - USS Houston (CL-81), Life Magazine's The Kissing Sailor, 2001. (Box 26, Folder 6)
    Donor: William Schramm
  - John R. Wisecup, After the Battle: Hintok! (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - John R. Wisecup, After the Battle: Hintok! USS Houston Survivors Association/Next Generation (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - John R. Wisecup, After the Battle: Hintok! and additional materials (photocopy). (Box 26, Folder 9)
- POETRY
  Poems are arranged alphabetically by author.
  - Anonymous. The Sinking of the Flagship Houston/Tis True,[Bicycle Camp, Java, ca. 1942-1945], with transcription. (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - A member of Marine Corps... The Houston Under Fire, undated (carbon copy). (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - A member of the Marine Corps... The Houston Under Fire. (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - A Navy Splice, (carbon copy). (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Jack Smith. Poetry. (Box 29, Folder 5-6)
  - Sophocles, extract from Chorus from Ajax, undated. (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Lloyd V. Willey, Battle Cruise of the Flagship ‘Houston,’ Bicycle Camp, Batavia, Java, ca. 1942 (photocopy). (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Lloyd V. Willey, Commissioning of the USS Rentz (FFG-46),June 8, 1984. (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Lloyd V. Willey, Commissioning of the USS Rentz (FFG-46),June 8, 1984 (photocopy). (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Lloyd V. Willey, Dream of a Prisoner-of-War,September 21, 1989. (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Lloyd V. Willey, Our Chaplain's Memorial - USS Rentz,March 20, 1986. (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - John Wisecup. Poetry and cartoons. (Box 29, Folder 13)
- SPEECHES
  Speeches are arranged alphabetically by author.
  - William A. Bernrieder, The United States Cruiser "Houston": The Pride of Our Navy and the City of Houston, October 11, 1930 (photocopy). (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Gavan Daws, Dedication of Lost Battalion and Houston Survivors Monument, National Memorial Cemetery of the Pacific (“Punchbowl”), Honolulu, May 4, 1994 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Joseph T. McCullen, Jr., Remarks By the Honorable Joseph T. McCullen, Jr. at the USS Houston Rededication Ceremony, November 11, 1974 (photocopy). (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - Sandy McNab, Toast, HMAS Perth and USS Houston Survivors 50th Anniversary Reunion Dinner, February 28, 1992. (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - Lt. Col. Nagamoto, Speech Delivered By Lieut. Col. Y. Nagatomo To Allied Prisoners of War At Thanbhyuzhat, Burma, October 28, 1942 (photocopy). (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - Lt. Col. Nagamoto, Speech given by Lt. Col. Nagatomo, Commanding War Prisoners Camp at Thambyuziat, Burma, October 28, 1942 (photocopy from Navy Dept.) (Box 29, Folder 19)
  - Tommy Payne, USS Houston (SSN-713), March 1, 1992. (Box 29, Folder 20)
  - Capt. Carl Ragsdale, Memorial Day 1942 Reenactment Ceremony, [ca. 1992] (photocopy). (Box 29, Folder 21)
  - Otto Schwarz, Remarks For the USS Houston Memorial, March 1, 1992. (Box 29, Folder 22)
  - Otto Schwarz, Memorial Speech at Ceremony for USS Houston (CA-30), February 29, 1992 (photocopy). (Box 29, Folder 23)
  - Otto Schwarz, We Bought Time, USS Houston Survivors Association Reunion, March 1, 2002. (Box 29, Folder 24)
    Donor: Robert Fulton
  - L.W. Rogers, USS Houston (SSN-713), March 1, 1992. Donor: (Box 29, Folder 25)
  - Terry Rentz Willis, The Houston Survivors Association, March 7, 1992 (photocopy). (Box 29, Folder 26)
  - Opening of the New Exhibition at the Changi Museum Honoring Americans who were Prisoners of War in Singapore, December 7, 2001. (Box 29, Folder 27)
- SCRAPBOOKS
  The scrapbooks in this collection are very fragile and bulky, and many of them contain loose items. Because of their condition, they cannot be photocopied, and decisions about photographing them will be made by the curator on a case-by-case basis. Materials may not be removed from scrapbooks for photocopying or photography.
  Scrapbooks are arranged alphabetically by creator.
  - William C. Batchelor, Jr., sister of, 1920-1997. (Box 31)
  - I. Roy Coats, scrapbook pages, 1934-1935. (Box 30)
  - J.C. Dinkel, 1930-1933. (Scrapbook Scrapbook 1)
    Donor: John Bartz
  - Arthur F. Durose, 1936 1949. (Scrapbook Scrapbook 2)
    Donor: Arthur F. Durose
  - Louis F. Garbs, [ca. 1931]-1939. (Scrapbook Scrapbook 3)
    Donor: Louis F. Garbs
  - Norrie C. Gardiner, [ca. 1931-1933]. (Scrapbook Scrapbook 4)
  - Norrie C. Gardiner, scrapbook pages [ca. 1942]. (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - Gilbert W. Hayes, scrapbook pages, [ca. 1938] (photocopies) (Box 29, Folder 28)
  - Robert Lamb, [ca. 1931-1933]. (Scrapbook Scrapbook 5)
    Donor: Robert Lamb
  - Frank Lima, 1931 1934. (Scrapbook Scrapbook 6)
    Donor: Frank Lima
  - Jack L. Smith, 1942 1956. (Scrapbook Scrapbook 7)
  - Jack L. Smith, family of, 1938-1945. (Scrapbook Scrapbook 8)
  - Svendburg, F., [ca. 1931 1933]. (Scrapbook Scrapbook 9)
    Donor: Bremerton Naval Museum
- INVITATIONS
  - Christmas Ball, December 28, 1935. (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Dance aboard USS Houston, October 29, [1930]. (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Dance invitation, August 17, 1934. (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Farewell Party, June 11, 1937. (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Farewell Party, June 11, 1937. (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Ship’s model and Cruiser Houston memorabilia acquisition, UH Libraries, 1979. (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - USS Houston (SSN-713) Launch (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - USS Houston (SSN-713) Launch, March 1981. (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - USS Houston (CA-30) Memorial Dedication Ceremony, November 11, 1995 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - USS Houston Survivors Association 50th Anniversary Tour, 1992. (Box 32, Folder 10)
- MENUS
  - Christmas, 1930 (photocopy). (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Christmas, 1935 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Christmas, 1935 (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Christmas, 1936 (photocopy). (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - Christmas, 1937. (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - Christmas, 1938 (photocopy). (Box 32, Folder 16)
  - Christmas, 1939. (Box 32, Folder 17)
  - Christmas, 1940 (two copies). (Box 32, Folder 18)
  - Christmas, 1940. (Box 32, Folder 19)
  - Christmas, 1940. (Box 32, Folder 20)
  - Thanksgiving, 1934. (Box 32, Folder 21)
  - Thanksgiving, 1934. (Box 32, Folder 22)
  - Thanksgiving, 1939. (Box 32, Folder 23)
    Donor: Otis Truelove
  - Thanksgiving, undated. (Box 32, Folder 24)
    Donor: James Ballen
- MEMORABILIA
  The Memorabilia series contains primarily objects that are related to the USS Houston (CA-30), the prisoner of war camps, or the USS Houston Survivors Association. The ship’s bell, the ship’s model, and two crew member uniforms are on permanent exhibit in the library.
  - Acey-deucy board and pieces, Takefu POW Camp, [1942-1945]. (Box 40)
    Donor: J.P. O'Grady
  - Address book, [1945]. (Box 32, Folder 25)
  - Airplane pieces, 1934. (Box 32, Folder 26)
  - Allied Forces Leave Pass, Camp No. 24, [ca. 1945]. (Box 32, Folder 27)
  - Baggage tag, [1942-1945]. (Box 32, Folder 28)
  - Bell, removed from ship prior to war. On loan from Lyndon Baines Johnson Library and Museum. (Exhibit EXHIBIT)
  - Belt buckle, 1940. (Box 37)
    Donor: Ray Sparks
  - Belt buckle, USS Houston Survivors Association, undated. (Box 38)
    Donor: C.W. Washburn
  - Billfold and flag, [1942-1945]. (Box 43)
  - Bowl and spoon, [1942-1945]. (Box 42)
  - Bumper sticker, USS Houston (CA-30), 2001. (Box 32, Folder 29)
  - Bumper sticker, USS Houston (SSN-713), undated. (Box 32, Folder 30)
  - Button, Ted “Itch” Schram, 2001. (Box 32, Folder 31)
    Donor: Family of Ted Schram
  - Calendar pages, 1992. (Box 32, Folder 32)
  - Card, Christmas, 1932. (Box 32, Folder 33)
  - Card, Christmas, 1935. (Box 32, Folder 34)
  - Card, Happy New Year, Changi Camp, Singapore, [ca. 1942-1945]. (Box 32, Folder 35)
  - Cigarette wrappers, beer labels, [1942-1945]. (Box 32, Folder 36)
  - Coins, commemorative (two), 2002. (Box 44)
  - Commemorative broadside, undated (Box 32, Folder 37)
  - Crossing the Line certificate, May 20, 1936 (printed digital copy). (Box 55, Folder 10)
  - Crossing the Line certificates, subpoena, May 20, 1936. (Box 32, Folder 38)
  - Crossing the Line songs, memos, July 1938. (Box 32, Folder 39)
  - Crossing the Line subpoena, May 20, 1936 (printed digital copy). (Box 32, Folder 40)
  - Crucifix and hearts, plexiglass, 1944. (Box 37)
  - Currency, [ca. 1940s]. (Box 32, Folder 41)
  - Currency, [ca. 1940s]. (Box 32, Folder 42)
  - Currency, [ca. 1940s]. (Box 32, Folder 43)
  - Currency,, [ca. 1940s]. (Box 32, Folder 44)
  - Dance card, Christmas Ball, December 22, 1934. (Box 32, Folder 45)
  - Flag, crocheted, 1978. (Box 50)
  - Flag flown on USS Houston by diver, October 3, 2001. (Box 34)
    Donor: Mason Logie
  - Flag flown on USS Houston by divers, March 1-2, 2002. (Box 35)
    Donor: Brad Smith
  - Flag made in POW camp. [Saigon, Indochina. 1945]. (Box 45)
    Gift of Doris Smith
  - Flag, undated. (Box 32, Folder 46)
  - Flags, [USS Houston (SSN-713) launch?], undated (Box 50)
  - Food supply band, [1942-1945]. (Box 36)
  - Form for writing to POWs, 1944. (Box 32, Folder 47)
  - Honorable Discharge case, [ca. 1940s]. (Box 32, Folder 48)
  - I.D. number, bath stamp, with description,, [1942-1945]. (Box 32, Folder 49)
  - I.D. tags, [1942-1945]. (Box 32, Folder 50)
  - I.D. tag, [1942-1945]. (Box 42)
    Donor: John Stefanek.
  - I.D. tag made by Lewis Biechlen, [1942-1945]. (Box 37)
  - I.D. tag and medallion, [1942-1945]. (Box 37)
  - I.D. tags, [1942-1945]. (Box 37)
  - Keys, [ca. 1942-1945]. (Box 37)
  - Knife, [1942-1945]. (Box 37)
  - Knife, ball bearing from air raid siren, Ohasi, Japan, 1945. (Box 37)
  - Letter [for athletic achievement], ca. 1940s. (Box 32, Folder 51)
  - Letter of authenticity for oil collected from USS Houston (CA-30), March 1, 2003, with photograph of oil. (Box 32, Folder 52)
    Donor: Bradley D. Gift
  - Liberty card, March 1, 19[??]. (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Liberty passes, USS Houston, [ca. 1930s]. (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Liberty pass, USS Houston, [ca. 1935-1939]. (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Liberty pass, USS Minneapolis, undated. (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Matchbooks, USS Houston, [ca. 1930s]. (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Matchbook, USS Houston, [ca. 1930s]. (Box 33, Folder 6)
    Donor: Steve Kovacs
  - Match boxes, 1945. (Box 37)
    Donor: Joan Winklareth
  - Medals, William Martin DeShields. (38)
    Donor: Donald F. DeShields.
  - Medals, Henry Nickel. (Box 39)
  - Medals, Capt. Albert H. Rooks. (Box Display box)
    On loan from Harold R. Rooks
  - Medical tag, 1945. (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Memorial cards, Frank Dethloff and Robert Lee Dethloff, 1989 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Model of USS Houston (CA 30) by Joseph T. Drummond, [ca. 1958] (Exhibit EXHIBIT)
  - Movie passes, 1940. (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Napkin, USS Rentz (FFG-46), undated (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Obituary of John C. Reas, laminated, 2003. (Box 33, Folder 11)
    Donors: Wallace and Vicki Keehr
  - Oil collected from USS Houston (CA-30) by diver, January 26, 2003. (Box 46)
  - Part of USS Houston's deck, undated. (Box 48)
  - Patch, Red Cross, [1942-1945]. (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Patch, USS Houston Survivors Association, undated. (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - Pennant, USS Houston (CA-30), [ca. 1935-1939]. (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - Pennants, USS Houston (SSN-713) launch, 1981. (Box 55, Folder 11)
  - Pillowcases, 1936. (Box 51)
    Donor: Mrs. H. E. Davis
  - Pipe and tin, [ca. 1942-1945]. (Box 47)
    Donor: James E. Reynolds.
  - Postage stamp, Panama Canal Zone, 1939. (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - Postcard, U.S. Naval Operating Base, Hampton Roads, Va., 1937 (printed digital copy). (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - Postcard, USS Houston, [ca. 1929]. (Box 33, Folder 16)
    Donor: Sean Ellerbee>
  - Postcards, Australians Under Fire, undated. (Box 33, Folder 17)
  - Postcards, Real Photo, USS Houston, [ca. 1930s]. (Box 33, Folder 18)
  - Postcards, USS Houston, [ca. 1930s]. (Box 33, Folder 19)
  - Postcards, USS Houston, undated. (Box 33, Folder 20)
  - Postcard, 1936 (Box 33, Folder 21)
  - Posters, Avenge the Houston!…with the Houston Volunteers,1942 (reproductions) (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - Poster, Gee!! I Wish I Were a Man, 1940. (Box 33, Folder 22)
  - Pouch, [1942-1945]. (Box 33, Folder 23)
  - Pouch, undated. (Box 36)
  - Prayer read at launch of USS Houston (CA-30), 1929 (Box 33, Folder 24)
  - Printed pictures, 1935. (Box 33, Folder 25)
  - Proclamation, Texas Lost Battalion/USS Houston Survivors Days, 1985. (Box 55, Folder 12)
    Donor: C. Hartung
  - Radio script, WHMA, 1945. (Box 33, Folder 26)
  - Receipt for POW package, [1942-1945]. (Box 33, Folder 27)
  - Red Cross convalescent kit bag, 1945. (Box 50)
  - Red Cross food transport label, [1942-1945]. (Box 33, Folder 28)
  - Rosary and box made from K-ration kit, [1942-1945]. (Box 37)
    Donor: Patricia Letze and Sharron Long
  - Rubbing of plaque at Whidbey Island Naval Air Station, [ca. 1986]. (Box 55, Folder 13)
  - School assignment by granddaughter of “Joe” Gans, 1998. (Box 33, Folder 29)
    Donor: Rich Gans
  - Sculpture made from ammunition, undated (Box 41)
  - Ship's service coupons, 1942. (Box 33, Folder 30)
    Donor: H.E. Brooks
  - Signatures, USS Houston Survivors, on matboard, [ca. 1997] (Box 55, Folder 14)
  - Signs, USS Houston Survivors Association. (Box 55, Folder 15)
    Donor: Leonard W. Kooper
  - Sleeve cuff, [1942-1945]. (Box 36)
  - Spike from Burma-Thai Railway, [ca. 1983]. (Box 48)
    Donor: Mr. & Mrs. J.M. Ballinger
  - Spike from Burma-Thai Railway, framed, inscribed, [ca. 1983]. (Box 44)
    Donor: John Schwarz
  - Spike from Burma-Thai Railway, [ca. 1983]. (Box 49)
  - Spoon, [1942-1945]. (Box 37)
  - Stamps, American Ex-Prisoners of War, [ca. 1950s]. (Box 33, Folder 31)
  - Stamps, World War II 50th Anniversary Commemorative Series, 1991. (Box 33, Folder 32)
  - Stamps, [1942-1945]. (Box 33, Folder 33)
  - Steel from USS Houston, 1928. (Ovs OVS)
  - Sticker, USS McClusky (FFG-41). (Box 33, Folder 34)
  - Stickers, USS Rentz (FFG-46). (Box 33, Folder 35)
  - Territorian Lottery: Battle of Australia (photocopy), [ca. 1990s]. z (Box 33, Folder 36)
    Donor: Jack Feli